Guide to the Stanford University, School of Engineering, Photograph Collection PC0139
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, School of Engineering, photograph collection
circa 1970-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. School of Engineering
PC0139
4.75 Linear Feet
402432 megabyte(s)
Collection consists of several accessions of materials. Accession 2010-026 contains portraits of faculty that were once on display in the department. Accession 2010-027 contains assorted photographs from the Design Division, circa 1970-1998, which includes casual portraits of faculty, meetings, and social events, one photograph album (1984-85), and one folder of clippings and brochures. Accession 2008-318 contains photographs and captions from a display in the Engineering Library on the silicon solar cell research group, along with some assembled reading materials. Accession 2010-053 pertains to the Engineering Library’s move to a new building in 1977 and includes negatives, contact prints, and selected mounted prints used in an exhibition.
General note
See ARCH-AM 2008-025 for solar cell and silicon chip associated with accession 2008-318.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of several accessions of materials. Accession 2010-026 contains portraits of faculty that were once on display in the department. Accession 2010-027 contains assorted photographs from the Design Division, circa 1970-1998, which includes casual portraits of faculty, meetings, and social events, one photograph album (1984-85), and one folder of clippings and brochures. Accession 2008-318 contains photographs and captions from a display in the Engineering Library on the silicon solar cell research group, along with some assembled reading materials. Accession 2010-053 pertains to the Engineering Library’s move to a new building in 1977 and includes negatives, contact prints, and selected mounted prints used in an exhibition.
Photoprints.; Stanford University. School of Engineering; Stanford University. School of Engineering. Students; Stanford University. School of Engineering; Stanford University. School of Engineering. Faculty.
- Photographs, Accession ARCH-2008-318
  - Images (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Captions (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reading materials (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Photographs, Accession ARCH-2010-026
  - Faculty: A-B (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Andreas, Adams, Arnold, Arrow, Ashley, Baganoff, Barkan, Bates, Benjamin, Birnie, Boudart, Bracewell, Breakwell, Brown, Bryson, Bube, and Buneman
  - Faculty: C (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Cannon, Carpenter, Carroll, Chang, Chao, Chilton, Chodorow, Connolly, and Cottle
  - Faculty: D (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Da Rosa, Dantzig, DeBra, Domonoske, Douglas, Dunn, and Durand
  - Faculty: E (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Eaves, Edward, Eliassen, Eshleman, and Eustis
  - Faculty: F (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Feigleson, Feigenbaum, Fish, Floyd, W. Flugge, I. Flugge-Lotz, Fondahl, Franzini, Fraser-Smith, and Fuchs
  - Faculty: G (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Gere, Goodier, Grant, and Green
  - Faculty: H (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Harman, Heffner, Helliwell, Hellman, Herriot, Hermann, Hetenyi, Hillier, Hoff, T. Hoover, Hoskins, Hsu, and Huggins
  - Faculty: I-J-K (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Inglehart, Jacobsen, Johnston, Kane, Karamcheti, Katsufrakis, Kays, Keller, Kincheloe, Kindy, Kino, Kline, Knuth, and Kruger
  - Faculty: L (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Lee, Lesley, Levinthal, Lieberman, Liggett, Lindau, Linsley, J. Linvill, W. Linvill, London, and Luckham
  - Faculty: M (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Macovski, Madix, Manne, Manning, C. D. Marx, G. Marx, Mason, Masters, May, Mayers, McCarty, McCluskey, McKim, Meindl, Mitchner, Moffat, and C. Moser
  - Faculty: N-O-P (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Niles, Nilsson, Oakford, Oglesby, Palmateer, Pantell, Parker, Pearson, Peterson, Pettit, Pound, and Powell
  - Faculty: R (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Rambo, Reid, L. B. Reynolds, W. C. Reynolds, Richards, Roberts, Roggeveen, and Ryan
  - Faculty: S (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Seifert, Self, Shah, Shepard, Sher, Sherby, Shevell, Shockley, Shyne, Siegman, Skilling, R. Smith, Spangenberg, Spicer, Spreiter, Stevenson, and Street
  - Faculty: T (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Teicholz, Terman, D. Thompson, V. K. Thompson, Tiller, Timoshenko, and Tuttle
  - Faculty: U-Y (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Ullman, Van Dyke, Vennard, Villard, Vincenti, Waterman, Weaver, Wells, White, Wilde, William, Williams, Wing, and Young
  - Oversize images of faculty: (Box 2)
    Frederick Terman, Samuel B. Morris, William Kays, John Hennessy, Theodore Hoover, Jim Gibbons, Joseph Pettit,
- Photographs, Accession ARCH-2010-027
  - Faculty, casual portraits: Felix Zajac, Larry Leifer, and Elliott Levinthal, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Faculty, casual portraits: Drew Nelson and 1 unidentified man, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty, casual portraits: Dennis Carter, Rolf Faste, Mark Cutkosky, Henry O. Fuchs, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty, casual portraits: Sherri Sheppard, Philip Barkan, Douglass Wilde, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Walking Chair, Prof. Leifer and others, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified meeting #1 undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified meeting #2 undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified meeting #3 undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified meeting #4, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Picnic event, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Retirement party, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Retirement party, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baseball game (black & white images) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beach event (possible division retreat 1995?) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Faculty photos (unidentified), 1994-95 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Social event on campus, undated but possibly 1970s (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Polaroid photographs possibly from demonstration of a device (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Prof. David Beach with old car (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Social events, assorted (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Social events, assorted (images with tape residue) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Lab; device [no people] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Postcards, 1987-88 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1985-98, brochure on Design Affiliates Program, and booklet on Design Division (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Negatives (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Negatives [in mylar sleeves] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Loose items from album (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photo album [some events noted but not individuals], 1984-85 (Box 2)
- Photos of move to new library, 1977; Accession ARCH-2010-053
  - Staff and helpers (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Old and new facilities (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Moving (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Contact prints and negatives (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photographs, Accession ARCH-2010-062
  - Mounted photograph of Halcott Cadwalader Moreno (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proof sheet for Clay Bates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of Kenneth Down (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Dwain Fullerton (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of Madelyn Hunt (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photograph of Leroy McGhie (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Proof sheets for William Nix (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Proof sheet for Prof. Quate (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proof sheet for Robert Street (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph of Lauress Wise (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence re photographs 2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: Emeriti Faculty Photos A--L (Box 1)
  - Notebook: Emeriti Faculty Photos M--Z (Box 1)
- Photographs, Accession ARCH-2018-037
  - 1990 Oct-2001 (Box 1)
  - Campus, Main Quad, People, SEQ, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Slides (Box 1)
  - Digital photographs, 402432 megabyte(s) (101,856 computer files)